Hello.
Can you hear me?
I can hear you.
Excellent.
Just
simply.
How about now?
Can you hear me now?
Yes.
Excellent.
Let me go through this.
You got any long weekend plans?
No, not really.
I was going to have long weekend plans.
My dog, anyway, my dog is tough to go get spade.
So
we're not doing that.
What about your dog?
Spade.
It's when dogs get when you snip a dog.
Oh, right, right.
Okay.
Suck.
Hold on.
So hold on.
Well, I'm.
Oh, Fan Delver.
That's what I'm looking for.
So there's a.
So I'm dyslexic, right?
So there's like times when I cannot spell things to save my life.
Oh, is it that?
That's how it works?
It works in a variety of ways, but for me, that's how it works.
When I was a kid, I used to get confused between on and no, those two words.
I am not an expert in the area.
I thought I.
I actually went and got myself tested because I'm so not an expert in the area.
Oh.
All right.
Okay.
I can't find the relevant music for this today.
So we'll just have to deal with, we'll just not have relevant music.
Okay.
Let me see if we hold on.
You can at least have.
Ah, there's some fun.
Okay.
All right.
Not for today's scene.
How dare they?
They set you up and then they tear you down.
That's all I have to say.
All right.
Okay.
So just to remind you of what was going on, let me just sent you that quick summary.
You just met with Harun Kost, right?
The Red Wizard of Thay.
Yeah.
Necromancer, who said he knew where the cave of Cocave was.
Sorry, not the Cragmaw Castle, which is your next hint as to where, what's his name?
Rock seeker.
Gundren Rockseeker is Iarno Albrek and your what's his name?
The spider.
Spider, yeah.
You had two quests.
You had one quest, which was to go deal with actually three quests.
You had a quest to go deal with some raiders, a quest to deal with a Banshee, and now, and then you decided that neither of those quests were cool enough, so you decided to go on yet a third quest.
No, I think he had a quest at Wyvern Tor.
Yeah, no, yeah.
He had a third.
His was the third quest.
Right.
Okay.
So there was, or was it the same quest?
Anyway, so here we are.
So you kind of arrived.
You've arrived at this location.
Let me just get the description up.
No, actually, it is true.
The Wyvern Tor is the same one.
Yes, you are correct.
It was my mistake.
My mistake.
Yeah, I chose Wyvern Tor.
Yeah, you chose one.
Okay.
Sorry, sorry.
The faint smell of smoke hangs in the air as you ascend a rugged ridge down the lower slopes of the hill.
50 yards away, a cavemouth opens up at the bottom of a ravine, hunkered down by a boulder 20 yards outside the cave.
Evidently keeping watch is a single bugbear.
That's what I see now.
Yep.
All right.
So what do you want to do?
So we are here.
Do I have the range to shoot an arrow?
You definitely have the range to shoot the arrow.
The question on the table is, you know.
Yes, you do.
You definitely have the range to shoot an arrow.
80 is the range, I think.
Okay.
So we can see only one bugbear standing over there.
In front of a cavemouth, right?
Yeah, yeah.
Okay.
You can ask your allies what they think you should do.
They are there.
They do.
Yeah, I'm going to head back and start a discussion.
All righty.
Hey, guys.
So I see a bugbear at the far end of the cave.
Yeah, a ravine.
At the ravine?
Okay, yeah, yeah.
So I was thinking I could use my shotbow and take that guy out, but he's kind of far, and I think I'll be able to make it.
What do you guys want to do?
Do you have any better idea to tackle the situation?
Well.
Okay.
So, I mean, so Pip says, well, the first thing we should do is to check to see if he's doing anything.
What do you mean he's doing anything?
Well, is he the kind of guard that sends his time thinking hard, or is he the kind of guard that, you know, is what kind of guard is here?
Well, to explore that, you need to go close to him.
And I think it's a bad idea going close to him.
Oh, you could get somewhat close to him, right?
I mean, he looks at you.
You can sneak, right?
I can sneak, but yeah, I guess you're right.
Okay, I can go as close as possible.
Let me try.
All right.
So I'll do a sneak pole.
Stealth.
Yep.
So 25.
All right.
You get close enough to be able to see him.
Okay.
He's got one eye, which is a milky film, right?
So he's basically blind in one eye.
And he leans on a salvaged pike.
Salvaged bike?
Pike.
P-I-K-E.
Oh, Pike.
Do you know what that is?
You don't.
It's a weapon.
It's a long, pointy weapon.
It's like a pole arm.
I think so.
Let's see.
Okay.
Like a spear.
Yep.
So he's got this.
He's kind of like sitting there guarding, guarding.
Do I see anyone else?
You want to try to see inside?
What you do notice about him is that he's kind of bored.
He feels like, you know, he's got that look of somebody who really doesn't want to be doing this.
All right.
So you're going to try to see what else you can notice?
Yeah.
All right.
You can't see into the cave.
It's too dark.
Right.
But you can definitely smell the cookfire smoke.
From inside the cave?
Yeah.
So there's definitely somebody else inside there.
So.
Can I use a mage hand and try to do some magic kind of thing, like, you know, throw off a spike or throw a stone at him, something like that, without being noticed?
Let's see.
I mean, you could.
Oh, you mean you could use it to throw it from a different location, for example.
Like, you could move your mage hand, you could place your mage hand 30 feet away, right?
So you could put it like over here.
Yeah, yeah.
And have it have it go there.
Yeah.
All right.
So that's a great plan.
What do you want to do with the rest of your party?
They're like 60 feet away.
They're very far away.
So they're like at least more than one round away from coming here.
So I want to give them here.
Get them where place them.
Or just click where you want them.
Here.
Okay.
Like, I guess they are not seen if they are here.
All right.
So you want to, let's say, roll their stealth.
Once they're, let me just see what their passive passive.
Stealth?
No, no.
Hold on.
Let me just do it.
Let me just save myself some time.
All right.
This guy's got some pretty strong stealth.
So if they and that's something that, so do you, do you, okay, so you're going to try to do that, right?
Okay, roll, roll, roll a group.
Well, we have to roll a group, pass it a stealth check.
So roll 3d6.
That's right.
Roll, let's roll 3d20 for all of the characters and see what they do.
So, all right.
Okay.
All right.
Unfortunately, he notices something.
So he steps over here.
What do you want to do?
He doesn't know what he's noticed, but he's noticed something.
So I still want to use my mage hand from the other side to distract him from the north.
All right.
So you're going to use your mage hand to distract him.
How do you distract him?
So behind him, assuming he's facing south.
Yep, he's facing south.
Yep.
All right.
So he should hear rocks roll down or, you know, maybe a stone hitting the wall.
Okay.
Yeah.
So he's hitting a wall.
Okay.
So once he does that, what do you want to do?
So he's going to turn around and then maybe, you know, do that again from the east and the west.
So he kind of thinks that there's someone, and I want him to call for help.
So you want everybody to come out?
Not everyone.
Like, you know, I want him to at least call another bumpy or maybe two.
Can I ask you?
That's what my expectation is: like, you know, if he.
But why?
Okay, so let me ask you a question.
I mean, I just want to make sure.
So there's this one guard.
Is your plan to get everybody out and have a free-for-all fight?
Or what's your plan?
Yeah, I mean, I'm expecting at least one or two of them to come out and then I want to engage in a fight.
All right.
Well, so, you know, Pip would have told you that the easiest way that it's much better to silently kill the sentry rather than to have everybody show up because it might be more than two.
That's what Pip would say, but he also would be like, you're the one, you know, it's like, you haven't led us wrong yet, Zenvon.
I mean, it makes sense, but I'm thinking if we can kill him without alerting others.
Okay, yeah, I guess it doesn't matter either way.
Like, it's, I feel using the mage hand is more effort for the same output.
Well, no, I mean, you've got him distracted.
Like, like, now he's fully distracted.
So if you were trying to do a surprise attack, this might be the right time to do it.
Oh, right.
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah.
Okay.
Right.
Remember, you guys get a big advantage when you have surprise, right?
Yeah.
So if your plan was to ambush him, this is not a bad way to start up an ambush.
Okay.
Yeah.
Makes sense.
So.
So do you want to have him head more towards your guys or do you want to have him head more away from your guys?
Head more away from my guys and then well, so hold on.
If you send him away, then remember, Pip can't hit him because he's too far away.
Well, no, no, no.
What I meant is like.
Do you want to go this arrow, this way, or this way?
Which way?
North or south?
No, he's going to stay there wherever he is.
But he just has the back turned towards Pip because of that.
Right, but yeah, but the problem is like this is 60 feet of open territory.
Okay.
And he's already suspected that somebody's over here.
He's already heard something, so he's looking towards the south.
Okay.
So, no, no, no, but is he distracted still if he's moving down south?
Well, he's kind of staring down south.
So now you have an opportunity to try to get you can either you can either confirm his suspicion and have him keep walking, see if you can get him to keep walking more south or point him in a different direction.
The only thing I want to make sure you remember, because you're new to this combat, is that 60 feet, like this represents the amount of distance Pip would have to cover before he could attack, and he can't, then he can't, and he wouldn't be able to attack in the first round.
Okay, okay.
Right.
I'm just trying, like, I just want to be like, the closer he gets to Pip, the better off you are.
The further away he is from Pip, the worse, the harder it is to kill him in one round.
That's my only point.
Okay, so when he suspects there is something towards the south behind the rock, I throw a stone using mage hand from the north.
He turns his back around, and then I would want Pip to move somewhere here into the ridge to attack in that time, but you know, and sneak and stay in position there.
All right, okay.
So, all right, so he comes over here.
All right.
He comes over there.
And so when he's over there, what is it that you do?
No, that's not what I meant.
But.
All right.
So, okay.
So you threw he's there.
Right.
He's there.
All right.
He heard some noise from the south because your guys blew their stealth check.
He can't see them yet.
So he's slow.
He's moving.
He's moving down.
He's moved like 10 feet down.
Okay.
Like move like 10.
Let's say he's come to here.
Now what do you do?
He's got his poke in front of him and he's looking and you can see him looking over his shoulder.
Roll and roll an insight check.
All right.
You notice nothing.
A bit tricky here.
Okay.
I want to use
Veyra as a bait because she looks like a sorceress, like a student.
Yes.
Right.
So I want Veyra to step out into the open and so that the bugbear can notice her and walk a little forward.
All right.
What does she say?
No, she doesn't say anything.
She is like, you know, she kind of shouting like, I'm lost here.
Like, can you help me?
And that way, the bugbear is walking like two more squares down south.
And then I'll attack from the back and Pip can attack from the front.
He's going to put Pip is going to be.
Okay, so you're basically trying to make Veyra look like she's some lost academic who doesn't know what's going on, right?
Yeah, yeah.
I'm trying to decide what Veyra's reaction is.
I thought a lot about this.
Okay, Veyra, Veyra is kind of like.
Veyra picks up her notebook.
She looks at the bug beer, realizes the bug beer.
She has enough time to dodge him.
So she steps up and stands in front, stands in front.
Now, the only question is: do you want to make her to make noise or just want her to be like, look confused?
Anything is fine.
Well, if she makes noise, she might attract other people from the cave.
Is your goal to get him?
Oh.
Yeah, so I think she just stands confused, not knowing what to do.
Okay.
So she sets up, she stands there and she's got her notebook.
Yeah, okay.
The bug bear sees her and growls and takes a step forward, not sure what to do.
All right, let's roll for, let's uh roll, let's roll to see what happens.
D20, right?
Yeah, hold on.
16.
Hold on.
So you roll the 16?
Yeah.
Are you having fun with the spells?
Yeah, I'm just trying to check how to use the marker to point.
Six.
The one you're looking for is the, if you're looking for the pointer, you see where the hand is.
If you click on the point, just above where it says the three.
Yes.
And double click, it's not working.
No, you don't double click.
You just point.
Click on hold.
Okay, okay, cool.
Okay.
Yeah.
The bug beer grunts something.
What language do they do?
Grunt something in common, muttering, just a tourist.
All right.
So as far as the just a tourist.
But he says it in the same way you might say, just a chicken I'm about to have dinner with.
Where I'm going to be having dinner and the chicken is going to be the food.
Okay.
That's the emotion.
So cool.
Just to give you the idea of the motion right now.
Yes, yes.
So it's the first one.
That's interesting.
I was looking for Ember's pony.
All right.
The next thing to do is to member dog can't have frozen bagels anymore.
She needs the thought.
Welcome.
Thought the bagels.
No, I'm just sorry to hear about her teeth.
She sits in half and she chews all sorts of random rocks and sticks and bagels and bones.
This is not a.
No, I know.
I'm just sad.
I'm sad for her teeth.
She's not going to, she's not going to.
Okay.
She chipped a couple of chips in her back.
She made teeth.
That's fine.
All right.
Okay.
So let's see.
So roll your stealth with advantage.
Yeah.
Eppa?
Oh, goes.
He goes.
All right.
With advantage.
That means roll again.
Wow, you ruled really badly.
All right.
Sister Maela.
So Veyra is the only one who gets a surprise round.
Oh.
So he notices me from the back?
No, you don't surprise him, is what I'm trying to say.
He notices you enough so you don't have surprise.
Although I guess if you're hidden, you would still have a sneak attack bonus.
So I'm going to go with the you don't surprise him, but I'm going to say that you were hidden.
Does that make sense?
Okay, okay.
All right, because he didn't notice you.
So you don't get a surprise round, which means you don't get to attack and then get it to attack before he gets to attack.
Does that make sense?
Yeah, yeah, correct.
So Veyra is the only one who gets a surprise round.
What does Veyra do?
I have to get her character sheet.
All right.
Veyra shoots and uses magic missile on him.
Veyra, that was not very good.
All right, does six points of damage with magic missile.
All right, the bug beer.
Um, and then she decides to one two.
Can I request a health bar on top of that button?
What hold on?
So the bug bear goes one, two, three, four, five, six.
He sees Pip, Sister Maela, and Veyra.
All right, Zenvon, you're up.
Yeah, can I request a health bar on top of the bug bear?
Well, no, because you're because you're hidden, you can use your ranged attack to hit him with and get your sneak attack bonus.
That is fine.
I'm asking like for a health bar on top of the bugbear, like the bugbear's health bar.
Oh, health bar.
Yeah.
I was hearing helper.
Oh, no, not a helper, health bar.
Sorry.
All right.
Okay.
Zenvon, you're up.
Can I use a short bow?
Yeah.
So it should do.
Right.
Rolling for shortbow.
Seven.
You rolled a seven.
Yeah.
All right.
This is that was that is a miss.
What?
No, I would be nice.
Like, can I get a secondary or something?
Something
no, but you might want to start running towards your party.
Okay.
The other I've the other thing you so remember, you have the ability to do bonus action.
So you're going to run over here
or are you going to run over there?
Yeah, here is fine.
Here?
So you're going to run along the ridge?
All right.
Are you going to try?
Okay.
I think do you have bonus actions that allow you to hide?
Do I have a bonus action that allows me to hide?
Dash?
Yes, yes, yes.
So you can choose to hide if you want.
Okay, I'll hide.
All right, so let me just see if you know.
All right.
Okay.
Sister Maela is like, she looks at the bugbear and says, turn shouts.
We can't let him get close to he.
We can't let him
warn the other guys.
She marches up to him and hits him.
And at least she smashes him with her mace and says, this is how it's done.
How much damage does she do?
She does
six points of damage.
All right.
Sister Maela.
All right, Sister Maela.
Okay, that's Veyra.
Veyra looks at him again and decides to cast another magic missile.
And this time she does 12 points of damage.
Oh, all right.
Pip goes over here, goes over here, and uses his sword.
I need to even make sure I remember what this is.
He has a special sword there, if I'm mistaken.
He's got a plus one.
He's got a plus one sword.
All right.
Good.
So, okay, so he's got plus three to attack.
Plus seven.
Plus five to hit.
All right.
So 20 plus five.
That work.
All right, he hits, which is good news.
And he kills the bug bear.
All right, the bug bear is dead.
Sister Maela says it's always a good thing to feel sad about killing one of the creatures in this world, but when you're dealing with that, but it was either us or him.
But I feel sad because he was blind in one eye.
Veyra says, Yeah, but I was his lunch.
I get it.
Sister Maela is like, that's very, it's very noble of you to, you know, to be, to, to, be, to thoughtfully care about the bug bears.
That is to your credit.
Well, okay, let's let's move on.
What can we do now?
All right.
So, um, Sister Maela says, well, if we leave the body here and somebody comes out, they may notice, they may notice, they may, they might, then all of our effort to try to get some kind of surprise might go to waste.
Okay, let's hide it in the bushes, hide the body in the bushes.
All right, so you're going to hide the body in the bushes?
Yep.
All right, so we'll put a bug bear body.
Yeah, like here.
Yes.
Right.
All right.
Okay, now what do you want to do?
Go peek inside.
Yeah.
Yes.
All right.
Yeah, I can't move her.
Who can't you move?
No, Maela.
Yeah, let me just go fix that.
Let me go fix that.
No.
Oh, yeah.
I think I can.
You can now?
I can.
Awesome.
All right.
That was.
Oh, they fixed it.
Oh, my God.
There was this bug where you would make the change, but then you had to create, like, even though it was linked to that token, you had to remove the token and add it.
I was like, that used to drive me nuts that they couldn't get that feature to work.
Oh, okay.
So, part of the reason why I kept not doing it is because getting it to work always involved, like it was very finicky.
But apparently, somebody decided to go fix it.
All right, Zenvon, you want to go look inside?
Wait, hold on.
Let me see.
I think you have a potion of invisibility.
I cannot see in the dark, right?
Or can I see in the dark?
No, but it's not dark.
I mean, you can, it's not black because there's a fire, remember?
Ah, right, okay, okay.
So, yeah, I want to like take a peek.
All right, let me take a peek.
It's a lot like pitch black.
Okay.
All righty.
All right.
Okay.
So you sort of peek inside there.
All right.
You see a bunch of you see what you notice a bunch of things, right?
There's four bug beers.
There's an ogre.
Yeah.
Right.
And then there's this one orc.
All right.
I will make sure that, let me just, let's see, let me just see what how this.
Why is the ogre big?
Hold on, give me one sec.
All right.
So as you look around, role, role and investigation.
Right.
Sister Maela, you don't notice anything, so Sister Maela pokes her head as well.
He's like, she doesn't notice anything, which causes Pip to, of course, want to take a look as well.
Yeah.
He notices that he's a military man, right?
So he notices, he looks around and says, you know, what's interesting about this group is that the orc is the weakest of all of these characters, and yet he seems to be the only one that has any authority here.
Like normally, an ogre is in charge.
So I don't know, but this seems like a very interesting situation.
How does he confirm that the orc is an authority here?
Well, he goes, look, now he tried to go, now look, Zenvon.
In the military, sometimes most of these creatures respond to whoever's the biggest.
So normally it would be the ogre in charge.
And an orc would be kind of like bringing them food left, right, and center.
But if you look at, right?
But if you look inside, he's the one sitting next to the fire, and everybody's sort of listening to him.
Okay.
That's a brilliant observation.
He goes, and so I'm just going to tell you that that tells me that he's the brains of the operation.
So, you know, I don't want to tell you how to do your job,
but my experience is with these kind of groups, and not with these kind of groups, but in the army, if you kill the leader in this kind of group, it's kind of a mob.
It's kind of a gang.
If you kill the gang boss, everybody else suddenly doesn't want to fight anymore.
That makes our job interesting.
I'm just want to throw that.
I just want to throw that out there, boss.
Or, you know, we could run in there and try to kill them all.
Last time we faced four bug bears, we had to run for our lives.
So I'm not entirely certain that's something we want to do.
Well, you make a point, but that's very valid.
So, what do you suggest?
Do you suggest to kill the orc from this far, or do you want to confront him?
Because if we confront him, like he's going to alert the bugbears on the Sister Maela goes, looks in a little bit carefully and says, Let me see what she's saying.
Let me have a look at what she'll
just do something.
So, I can create any illusions, right?
Yep.
And I will be hidden behind the illusion.
I'm sorry.
Will I be hidden behind the illusion I create?
Let's suppose I create a football, and can I be seen behind the football?
No.
You cannot be seen behind the football.
Okay, I have a weird idea.
I want to create an illusion of the guarding bugbear.
And what?
Okay, keep going.
Yeah, I want to create an illusion of the guarding bugbear, and then all four of us walk behind him without being seen to the orc.
I mean, just to be clear, you all have ranged weapons.
We do, but you know, I'm afraid, like, within just one attack, I don't think we can kill.
Okay, so you guys want to like gang up on him, right?
Yes.
All right.
So, so the only problem is the illusion, I believe, is stationary.
Stationary?
Says minor illusion.
Yeah, so what is it?
What's the spell called?
Minor illusion.
You create a sound or an image of an object within range that lasts for the duration.
See the descriptions with the footage.
No movement.
It must be no larger than a five-foot cube.
The image can't create sound.
Yeah, so five-foot cube means it could be the shape of a bugbear.
So you could create a bug bear image that you can make, so you can make an illusion of the bugbear over here.
Let me just put, let me just draw here, right?
So you make an illusion of the bugbear over here, so that, and then you could rush the illusion, right?
Does that make sense?
Yeah, yeah.
You can't hide behind it.
So, what you're essentially trying to do is use that to get us to surprise him.
Why cannot I hide behind him?
But he doesn't move.
No, he moves.
I mean, there's nowhere written that he cannot move.
Yes, if you look at the illusion, the minor illusion, maybe I'm looking at the wrong definition of the spell.
Hold on.
It's entirely possible that I am looking at the wrong definition of these spells.
Illusion cantrap.
Yeah.
Spell, minor illusion.
You create a sound or image of an object that lasts for a round.
Creature takes an action, blah, blah, sound.
Yeah, so physical interaction reveals that it's an illusion, but otherwise it can move.
No, it doesn't say you can't move it.
Let me just check something again.
All right, so you can't move it.
It does not support movement.
It's cast.
You create a sound within an object that lasts for their duration.
So, no, you cannot have it move.
Okay.
All right.
So I read the rules.
That is not one of the things that this spell allows you to do.
But we can hide behind it and
charge.
Yes.
So, yeah, you can definitely do that.
And certainly, if you put him there, I will give you an advantage on your stealth to attack him.
Okay.
What?
Awesome.
Let's do that.
Okay.
All right.
That is a very clever solution to the problem.
Okay.
Let me just go to the roll 20.
That was a very clever solution of the problem.
All right.
Okay.
So Veyra is going to be over here.
Sister Maela is going to be over here.
Zenvon.
I'll
just do this.
Okay.
Why don't you guys roll your stealth with initiative?
With advantage.
Yeah, with advantage.
Let's see.
Can you guys do better this time?
All right.
Good.
Sister Maela.
Wait, wait, wait.
Yeah.
With advantage.
Yes.
All right.
Yeah, you definitely crossed the threshold.
2D20.
Sister Maela did as well.
Pip.
Pip did not.
And what about?
Okay, so two, two.
All right.
So Zenvon and Sister Maela get to attack with surprise.
Pip and Veyra have to wait for their turn in the normal initiative order.
All right.
Yeah.
So let's give it.
Can you roll your initiative?
We can keep your old initiatives or you can re-roll.
It's up to you.
No roll.
No, fine.
Okay.
You want to reroll?
Rero.
It's always fun to roll the dice.
Okay, one more please.
Sorry.
What did you roll?
Fine.
Happy with this.
All right.
That's not what I wanted.
All right, Zenvon.
Are you going to rush in to try to kill the guy?
Yes.
All right, you have surprise, so you can attack him with your sneak attack bonus.
Yeah.
Yeah, so I was going to use the Nick.
All right.
So you can move away?
Not move.
Okay, wait.
I'll use my wax so that I can hit twice.
All right.
You get advantage on the second roll, right?
Yeah, yeah.
All right, go for it.
Short sword.
Yes.
Okay.
I'm going to use my short sword.
That is a hit.
Roll for damage.
And if you click the roll damages in roll 20, it'll tell you what it'll roll the damages from there.
Okay.
Seven points of damage.
Not exactly the best roll you could have had.
Yeah.
Then I have seven.
Yep.
Rolling again.
14.
Oh, that is also a hit.
Okay.
Rolling for damages.
Seven.
Ah, he's down to one hit point.
Oh, cool.
All right.
We established Sister Maela had advantage, right?
So, Sister Maela comes in.
One, two, three, four, five.
Wait, the second attack was supposed to be an advantage for me, right?
I did not.
Oh, roll with advantage.
Yes, roll the second time or D20.
D20.
That's a miss, I guess.
Yeah, that would have been a mess.
All right, she's actually got two hit points.
I miscalculated it.
Okay, so he's got two hit points.
Sister Maela.
Sister Maela, you're breaking my heart, Lady.
All right.
Sister Maela, you broke my heart.
Yes, you did.
I guess it's Pip next.
All right.
Okay.
So, shall I take this back?
See, one of these bugbears.
All right, so she misses.
So.
Oh, there's a 15, right?
No, I just realized when you have a surprise, the rules are different than they used to.
Then I used to remember them, so I just had to re-change something.
All right.
Okay.
So now we go through the initiative normally.
Sister Maela, you're up.
Sorry, Zenvon, you're up again.
I'll use the short sword again.
All right.
By the way, because this, yeah, go for it.
Go.
Okay.
Roll to hit.
Ah, that's a miss.
Roll to hit again?
All right.
Advantage or no?
You don't have.
Oh, yeah, you do have advantage.
Yes, yes.
Now you have advantage.
Yes.
Okay, so rolling again.
Hey, yes.
Yes.
Okay.
Rolling for attack.
Oh, wow.
He's dead.
No, no, he's not just dead, right?
Like, you take your sword.
This is the scimitar, right?
It's a short sword.
No, you use your sort.
You have to sort sword swords and a scimitar.
Remember, you have one in each hand?
Uh-huh.
They do the same amount of damage.
Okay.
Oh, yes, yes, yeah, yeah.
Right.
And so you hit him with the sword sword, and he kind of loses his balance.
And then you take your scimitar and just like cut his throat open and he splatters.
He reaches for his neck.
He reaches for his neck dead.
All right.
Let's see what happens.
Okay.
Let me just make sure I know what happens.
All right.
Okay.
So.
And you'll just want.
All right.
This bug bear kind of was like.
Check out this YouTube video.
Which one?
The one I sent in the chat.
All right.
Oh, which chat?
Zoom chat.
Sorry.
I asked, like, welcome to the.
Every time I use this, I feel like I'm using Google products.
That's the head.
Okay, yes.
That's the scene.
Yes.
That is definitely, that is definitely the vibe.
All right, where are we?
He's dead.
We both are inside.
Pip and Veyra are outside.
All right, hold on.
So, okay, so this bug where you're seeing him die goes, I'm out of here.
13.
What?
Now, he's running away.
Now, if you attack him, he's going to stop running away.
Do you let him run away?
Where is he running?
Like outside or like into the cave somewhere?
No, he's running outside.
He's like, I'm done.
What about the other bugbears?
Have they noticed this?
Well, yeah, they just saw their boss killed, right?
So, all of them, including Augur.
Yes, everybody's noticed.
And so, the re so take if you want to use your insight, use your insight for a moment.
Yeah, I'm going to use my insight.
I don't get anything.
Well, that's bad.
All right.
Can I use my perception?
Yeah, roll your perception.
Okay.
What you perceive is that the bug bears kind of are like, I'm at, like, see him dead and like just want to get out of here.
The ogre is furious and wants to go kill you.
Okay, I'll let the bug bears run away then.
You're going to let the bug bears run away?
Yeah, just fight with the ogre.
All right, so he runs out here, runs through here.
Pip and Veyra let him run away.
Veyra's about to try to kill him, and Pip reminds her what the plan was.
Okay.
Remember, Veyra has a thing with killing people, right?
Yep.
All right.
Sister Maela, seeing the ogre, the bug bear dead, shouts, you know, if you want to live, be somewhere else.
The bug bears get the point and kind of make, don't, don't get in her way.
The ogre is kind of pissed off, calling them a bunch of cowards and blah, blah, blah.
And that his beloved Brugor, Axe Biter, whom he loved dearly, and you killed him, you bastards.
So what's he going to do next?
Maela's going to attack, is what's going to happen.
So Sister Maela is going to attack.
But no, what I'm trying to tell you is that he's emotional.
Apparently, he was emotionally invested in the bug beer.
No, in the in what's his name?
The orc.
Yeah, the orc.
Where is this?
Let me just get open her character sheets.
I don't keep my life a little bit easier.
Oh, it's done.
So she's going to use her sacred flame.
And he blows it.
So he takes 10 points of damage.
She does it from over here.
So she calls on sacred flame and it falls on his head.
The ogre howls.
Bug, you kill Brugor.
Me eat you alive.
All right.
Yeah, another bug bear runs out.
Okay.
Pip.
It's Pip's turn.
Pip is outside.
Yeah, so Pip comes over here and runs over here and decides that this is a good time to not miss.
He's like, please, baby, don't let me miss.
Yep.
Oh, he also has that, you know, the fancy sword.
Yeah, he's got a plus one magical sword.
That is true.
Okay.
All right.
All right, what does he do?
Where's his damage?
Okay.
D4 plus five.
All right.
So Pip strikes with his sword.
Does he hit?
Yes, he hits.
Or he hates absent.
D8 plus three.
Six points of damage.
All right.
He's going to use an action surge.
And he misses on a second attack.
All right.
Okay.
These two guys have gone to the wind.
All right.
The next bug bear.
This one also runs out.
And, you know, he's gone to the wind.
Okay.
Gog.
It's Gog's turn now, yes.
Uh-huh.
Gog.
All right.
Raises his great club and tries to bring it down on Pip and misses.
How could I miss?
All right.
This bug bearer also decides he's, you know, there's a time and a place for bravery, and this is not it.
Okay.
It's kind of weird.
Like, you know, normally these guys should have been able to handle.
So there's something there's something weird going on about these four bug bears and this and this ogre that you don't know.
All right.
He's let's get rid of him.
Veyra.
Veyra steps over here.
Let's see what her spell situation is like.
I already used magic missile twice, so she's going to use a firebolt.
Let me move part of the way.
So she's going to.
Oh, he can be there.
She's the firebolt.
Okay.
Five foot cubed is like this much volume.
Right.
Yeah.
Firebolt is this big.
Okay.
You Veyra can aim through you.
This is not first edition rules.
All right.
Where actually there was a 50% chance you would get hit, regardless of a two-hit roll.
She hits him for one glorious point of damage.
Oh, shit.
Okay.
All right.
Zenvon, you're up next.
I want to use the spell true strike.
Okay.
So that's what you is.
I've never done it, so it's my first time.
Let's see what happens.
The attack uses your spell casting ability for the attack and damage rolls instead of using strength or dexterity.
So what's the spell casting?
Arcana?
No, no.
If you go to your character sheet and you look up above it, like where you look where it says spells, the spells you can cast.
If you show me your screen, I'll show you where it is.
One second.
You see it?
Yeah.
So you see this one?
No, right, right.
Yeah, yeah, this one.
Okay.
All right.
Stop sharing.
So instead of using your normal to hit, you use plus four.
You use that.
Okay, so it's 23.
All right.
And that is.
I believe it's a hit.
And then should I roll for damage again, or is this for the damage?
Okay, so you get add plus four to hit and then plus four to damage.
So what did you what did you attack with?
True strike.
Okay.
I can use the radiant effect.
So damage.
Hold on.
True strike okay.
One second.
I need your help again.
Okay.
So let's start.
Sorry, let me pause you for a minute.
What weapon are you using to attack?
Hold on, my son's asking me for something.
Give me one second.
I got it to strike.
All right.
We're going to share my screen once I need your help to understand what happened.
So I clicked on this.
Okay.
All right.
So let me.
Yes.
And I got this one.
So I have to select a D20.
No, no, you click on click on it.
No, no.
So, all right.
For to do the damage, right?
You don't have to click on the radiant.
That is just to that that is not what you have to click on You just click over here Oh Okay, okay, yes Still brings this one hold on what does it do?
I can choose a dice Hold on hold on let me give you let me sync
all right so um so the way you do it is you do to you to do your attack you click on this button over here yes that's what I did first so I got 23.
All right.
Then for damage, right, you would roll a what weapon are you using?
Go to actions?
I'll use a short sword.
All right, so what you do is you just roll.
So the easiest thing to, if you're using a short sword, right?
Yeah.
It would be D6 plus four instead of plus three.
Does that make sense?
Okay, okay, yeah.
All right.
Yeah.
So just add one to whatever you roll.
Okay.
So I'll click this.
Roll.
No, no, no.
You can click on the short sword damage and add one because like whatever it rolled, add one.
12.
12 points of damage.
What did you attack with your short sword, right?
You can stop sharing now if you want.
Okay.
Thanks.
All right.
Okay.
So with your short sword, is that what you did?
So you rushed up to here and hit him with your sword for 12 points of damage.
Yep.
All right.
Now do you want to attack again with your scimitar?
Yes.
Okay.
All right.
Nine points of damage.
No, that was a miss.
Remember?
You have to roll the hit.
Oh, okay.
Okay.
Let me.
You roll damage.
You rolled your natural 20, I guess.
Did you roll a natural 20?
All right.
So that is.
So the way you do a natural 20 is if you click, just click, do you see where it says roll damages in the roll 20?
Yeah, yeah.
Now, yes.
Just click that button.
Okay, cool.
All right.
And so it's total damage is 10 points of damage because you already used your critical damage, your critical attack, your sneak attack.
So you do 10 points of damage.
To help you understand how this works, because it's like non-obvious.
See the first one that says slashing damage?
Yes.
That's how much you do from your weapon.
All right.
Your sneak attack.
Yes.
Sneak attack damage, you know what that is.
The critical damage is you basically roll another D6.
And your sneak attack critical damage is you basically roll your sneak attack damage again.
And so that's how you get to 29.
Okay.
Right.
But because you've already used your sneak attack bonus, you only add the slashing damage and the slashing critical damage.
Does that make sense?
Makes sense.
Yes.
Yeah.
It's just, you know, we're doing math.
All right.
So 30.
Yeah.
So she's down to 20.
Can you can see his health bar, right?
No.
There we go.
Yeah, I see it now.
Yes.
All right.
It's a huge creature.
Yeah.
Sister Maela uses her sacred flame again.
And let's see.
Does he make a saving throw?
No, he makes the saving throw.
All right.
Pip.
Pip's already used as bonus.
So.
He misses.
All right.
Gog swings his swings his mace and misses.
Veyra.
Veyra shouts, hey, boss, should I use my last spell?
Go ahead.
Make it count.
All right.
She uses her last magic missile, and this time does 15 points of damage.
Yes.
All right.
Zenvon, you're up.
Before I kill him, I want to get some information from him if I can.
So since he's almost to his knees, I want to talk before attacking.
All right.
Hold on, hold on.
You can give me a sec.
It's definitely, that is definitely an option.
Okay.
So what are you going to try to do?
Does he have a name?
Yes, you did hear his name.
He did refer to himself as Gog.
Gog, yes, yes.
Hey, Gok.
Listen, we did not intend to hurt you or your boss, but we had to help our friend Hamun Kost and also protect the land from all the threats and the robberies that you guys have been doing.
I just wanted to know before we finish the business, like why you have been doing, and do you know anything about Hamun Kost?
Tell us what has happened in the past.
All right.
Are you trying to do it diplomatically?
So roll your persuasion.
Natural 20.
Did you roll a natural 20?
Yes, sir.
All right.
Hold on.
Let me get something to drink.
All right.
One second.
Okay.
So,
so your question, you go, guys, so you ask, what is it that you asked him?
Just to remind me.
I wanted to know.
No, I just tell him that we are to help our friend Hamun Kost and if he knows what is the story behind the relationship between the skies and the Hamun Kost.
Hamon mentioned that you guys, these guys have been bothering him.
Okay, so why have you been bothering?
Okay, so he looks at you and goes.
He looks at you and goes, you killed Brugor!
Brugor!
And you can gather that they had some kind of romantic relationship.
It's kind of awkward.
And he looks at you and goes, Brugur!
Brugor say, Brugor, boss!
Brugor!
He starts crying.
Okay.
He looks at you.
He looks at you and goes,
Brugor say, attack.
He looks at you, goes, who the heck is...
He doesn't know who Hamun Kost is.
You're going to have to describe him to him.
Oh, okay.
Interesting.
He doesn't know who he is.
So Brugor says attack and they attack.
That's it.
Okay.
So this guy doesn't know anything.
Fine.
Kill him.
I will.
Okay.
You're cold back.
Sister Maela's like, sounds good to me.
I never liked ogres.
She casts, she makes her saving throw.
Gog is outraged and enraged at this point in time.
All right.
Pip, Pip.
It's Pip's turn.
And kills him.
Sister Maela turns.
Do you applaud?
Do you like literally clap your hands?
Yay.
Good job, Sister Maela.
No, no, that was Pip.
Oh, that was Pip.
Yes, sorry.
Sister Maela looks at you and goes, dude, you're cold.
I have to be sometimes, you know.
She goes, you are really cold, man.
Did you just forget that I was feeling bad for killing the bugbear who was blind?
She pauses and goes, I didn't say you weren't kind.
I mean, but that was cold.
You try to negotiate with him, decides he has nothing to add, and just kill him?
Yes.
She pauses.
Personally, I wouldn't have wasted time on the negotiation.
I would have just killed him.
But, you know.
Veyra is very pleased.
All right.
You want to keep looking around?
Yeah, of course.
They robbed a lot of people.
So there must be a lot of treasures around.
Yes, shouldn't there?
So I go to this corner.
Pip goes to this corner.
Veyra goes here.
All right.
Yeah.
We four are searching the cave.
Okay, you're searching the cave.
Yep.
Okay.
So as Pip as where is Zenvon.
Nothing.
I just was trying to see where you guys went.
All right.
So
as you're walking around, you notice a strange drawing.
Drawing on the wall.
Okay.
You see, first, you see, it's made of charcoal.
Do you get you step back to look at it or do you ignore it?
Do I want to look at it?
All right.
It's a figure.
You notice it's a figure.
As you stare at it some more,
as you stare at it some more, you notice that it's a looks like a goblin.
But as you look at it some more, you notice it has a crystal jutting from its skull.
Black crystal?
Nope.
A crystal.
It's in charcoal.
I mean, it could be black, but it's right.
So imagine here, let me just
Okay, so imagine, like, let me see if I can do this by hand.
Here, I'll do it in the world 20.
So, it's
like
so the crystal, is that real, or is that also drawn in charcoal?
It's all it's drawn in charcoal.
Oh, I see, okay, okay.
And the other thing you notice, yeah, so you see a goblin with a slightly off shape, but you don't know if that's a child's, if that's just a bad artist, and with a crystal on it.
Okay, okay.
I'm gonna call Veyra.
Hey, Veyra, come look over the.
I see a drawing here on the wall.
All right.
Does this figure seem familiar from one of the books that you have read?
Veyra,
all right.
Her
so her crystal flares.
Oh, okay.
Faintly.
She looks at it and goes, ha,
and reminds, and she goes, she looks and goes, This is the third such strange goblin we've seen.
Remember what Sildar told us?
No.
She pulls out her notes because that's what she does.
She keeps notes.
Let me just see.
She says, I don't want to reveal too much.
No, that's not what I want.
They seem.
All right.
So,
okay.
I put this in the Discord chat.
This is what Sildar told you when he was
when he was captured.
Strange problem with an elongated head was with the Kragma band that we give it sort of
the goggle and gave the bad feeling.
Kragma band faint and armor picture.
So when Veyra had written that name last time, the crystal had blown.
You're not what Ruxith wants.
Okay.
Pip goes over here and says, Well, that's interesting.
But he's not actually talking about the statues.
He's talking about the treasure he found.
Oh.
Yes, right.
He finds he finds an unlocked treasure chest.
Right.
And so he goes, well, thank God.
He goes, well, it's good.
It's a good thing that Harbin Wester was going to give us some money.
Yeah.
Do you know why?
No.
Well, that's why I said, like, look at this.
This is a disgrace.
What kind of bandit only has 180 silver pieces, 15 electrum pieces, and three bottles of perfume?
That seems odd for people who have robbed, you know, for bandits who have robbed a lot of travelers.
Veyra goes, you do remember that nobody comes this way, right?
Right, but these guys, I guess they attack all the travelers on the highway, I suppose.
Yeah.
This is just their hideout.
Yeah, you know, she goes, she pauses and says,
that's a really good connection.
So, hear me out.
I've got this crazy idea.
Go on.
It's all connected.
The bug beers, the strange goblins, the crystals, my mentor.
And she starts drawing connection after connection after connection.
Oh, wow.
Okay.
And, you know, she's like, she starts, she shows you this picture where she's got goblins pointing, you know, the crazy arrow.
Yeah, the detective thing.
Maela looks it over and says, I think you're missing an arrow.
She looks at it.
She looks at him and she stands and stares, where?
And Maela's laughing because she knows that Veyra is going to spend the next 20 minutes trying to find out which connection.
Oh, shit.
Right.
So, does the connections make sense, or do I need to know the connections?
You can, you so, so you roll, and so you can ask her.
Okay.
Roll insights.
Right.
Oh, sorry.
It's a five.
No, it makes no sense to you.
Okay.
And from Veyra, and you can't tell whether Veyra is just like trying to see patterns where they don't exist or there are real patterns.
Yeah, I'm not sure it makes sense to me, Veyra.
What's the final conclusion of your connection?
She goes, I don't know, but it all points to somebody in charge doing something awful.
Well, I guess Hamun can give us more information about that.
And I guess things are lying in the kragma castle.
And that's where we can find our answers.
She goes, exactly.
And so she puts, that's the arrow that's missing.
And so she draws a little castle and then starts points all the arrows to the castle.
The castle.
Okay.
That's where we have to go.
She looks at Sister Maela with this look of, I found it.
Right.
Yeah.
A sense of pride.
No, you know, a sense of, you know, I found a missing arrow.
Right.
Yeah.
Sister Maela, Sister Maela's got that look of.
You know, just like sighing, closing her eyes.
She says a little prayer to her god because she wants to avoid saying anything mean and nasty.
All right.
Okay, let me just mark down the treasure.
I have a Google spreadsheet, right?
We have a Google spreadsheet for this.
No, I don't have a Google sheet.
All right, that's because I don't need Google Sheets anymore.
I will put it in the Discord.
We were putting in the Discord chart earlier.
Yeah, yeah.
So 160 silver pieces, 15 electron pieces, three times five vials of
perfume.
Five GP each.
All right.
Not exactly, not exactly the big robbers here.
Yep.
All right.
I presume.
So do you want to head back to Hamun and then get the information about Kragma Castle?
Probably not a bad idea.
All right.
Before we leave, Pip, since you killed the ogre, I want to give you half of the silver pieces and one of the vials of the perfume.
Veyra goes, boss, I thought this was a group where we split things evenly.
Sure, but the ogre was very big and he got the last kill.
So I thought, you know, maybe, and I've not done anything for Pip on the launch.
It's not that you guys will not get anything, but in the next, you know, maybe whoever gets the last kill will.
So is this what we're doing now?
There's kill bonuses just in a happy mood.
So she goes, well, why don't you give him from your share and we'll get the normal share?
Sure.
Okay, Pip.
Here's what we'll do.
You can have my share and they'll get their share.
Everybody's very happy now.
Yes, awesome.
Okay.
I give my share to Pip.
That sounds like a plan.
All right.
You head over to the old owl well.
Right.
Okay.
Amoon is here.
Yeah, he's there, right?
So this is.
Hold on, hold on, hold on.
Hold on, let me just make sure you should be able to see him, right?
Yeah.
I can see him.
This time I shout without catching the attention of the zombies and ask Hamun to come out.
Tell him that the threat at Wyvern Tor has been mitigated.
Okay.
So the zombies are all in here.
You just say, you know, as you head back, you remember some of the zombies that you saw looked a little bit different.
Oh, you know, like one of them looked like a red wizard.
All right.
Okay.
Meaning that it was somebody obviously who came with him.
Right.
And another guy, another zombie over here looks like it was a guard of some kind.
Okay.
All right.
The rest of them look like general peasants that happen to have been in the wrong place at the wrong time with a powerful wizard, Red Wizard.
Amun is delighted.
Hamun sees you and he says, Ah, tell me, tell me, Pip, what sorry, Zenvon, tell me what news you have.
Tell me only good news.
Well, Hamun, the good news is the threat has been extinguished at the Wyvern Tor.
We killed the boss and the ogre, and the bugbears ran away.
Wonderful.
Wonderful, wonderful, wonderful.
And if I recall, I promised you a meal.
Yes, and also some information.
Yes, well, it's uncivilized to not have the meal first.
Sure.
Yeah, we clap.
He claps his hands.
All right.
And he's it's a very good meal.
And so, one of the things that you notice about like it's a very good meal, and like it's kind of like bizarre that this guy has spent this much money on this meal.
Okay, rather, like not so much on the meal, like on the serving part.
No, hold on,
all right.
So, no, he's obviously somebody who enjoys the finer things in life, right?
Um, and so, and one of the zombies is sort of uh the red wizard zombie is sort of acting as the waiter.
So, you basically have this zombie serving you food, okay?
It's very kind of like creepy.
Um, he's um, they're sitting around this table having dinner, there's a nice little fire.
Uh, Hamun says, Please, please enjoy the food.
You, it's it's actually very well-cooked food.
My apprentice has been serving me well, perhaps a little better on death than he did.
Um,
uh, my, my, my, my, my, uh, my, uh, what is it, my apprentice warden is serving me so much better in death than he served me in life.
Who was he before?
Was he your servant as well?
He told you who he was, his apprentice.
It was a right.
I was confirming.
You know, for some reason, I have my suspicions on Hamun.
I don't know.
It's just because he's a red wizard or something.
I fully don't trust him, but you know, it's just within us.
Okay, so you don't trust him as he's sitting.
So tell me, what did you find?
What happened?
You tell him what happened?
Yeah.
So the party was in a cave, and then we did a, we sneakily attacked the sentry and then took out the boss first, and then the entire party collapsed.
Wow.
But there was something strange that we found on one of the cave walls.
Like there was a figure of a goblin, goblin drawn in charcoal, but there was a crystal-shaped thing on his head.
That was strange to me.
Do you happen to know anything about that?
All of a sudden, his demeanor, which was kind of like, you know, happy, like relaxed, suddenly stops.
And you suddenly realize that why he is a powerful wizard.
And he kind of looks at you.
And his hands sort of fall down like this.
And he says, I want you to say exactly what you saw again.
Well, Veyra can give you the exact details.
Veyra, would you like to tell what you saw on the wall?
All right.
Hamun looks at you and says, fascinating.
Fascinating.
Very interesting.
And you said, Veyra, you've seen this before.
Yes.
He pauses.
This is extremely interesting information, Veyra.
And
he goes, I don't know what it means.
You can try rolling your insight to see if you can tell he's lying or not.
Well.
He goes, you rolled at 12, right?
You can't tell whether he's telling the truth or not.
Oh, okay.
Hamun looks at you carefully and says, Well, it would seem that my research in this area may actually prove to be very valuable.
Hamun, if you don't mind, could you explain me in simpler terms?
Is this something we should be worried of?
So, what do you know about this crystal and these black stones?
Veyra is about to blurt out everything.
Do you let her tell her everything?
No, no, actually, no.
So, no, we just, no, we are not aware of those things, but on the way to Phandalin, we saw a black crystal somewhere on the way and then it disappeared.
Roll an insight check.
You again, don't notice anything.
Roll your other allies, roll for your other allies.
Just roll 3D20, and we'll see what happens.
Ah, you got matched with me.
All right, Pip.
Pip realizes that Hamun knows it that Hamun shows an not like excitement.
Like he's excited when you tell him about the black obelisk.
Like he is that this is something he, this is like his, you can see his energy level pumps just for a moment.
And he hides it again.
Yes, he hides it again.
Okay.
And he pauses and he says, Well, let me say something for you.
My dear boy, he looks at Pip.
I happen to be an expert archaeologist.
And my expertise happens to be the Netheril Empire, and I happen to have more than a passing knowledge of Netheris,
the language of the ancients.
And he goes, for example, you see that sword you have?
Yes.
Yes, it's a sword that is made with forged with diamonds and all the other precious stones.
It once belonged to a great knight named Aldith Tresendar, known as the Black Hawk.
Tresendar, the name seems familiar.
Yeah, Tresendar Manor.
Tresendar Manor.
No, I'm just, you know, I know.
I was going to.
Yeah, that's one of my dialogues.
What you're saying is I like.
Okay, I didn't.
I thought you were asking me, sorry, but that was very, very good role playing.
Give yourself a point of inspiration.
Thank you.
Tresendar Manor, yes.
And Aldith Tresendar.
Okay.
And so he goes, as you can tell, I have made a bit of a habit of learning everything there is to know about this area.
And so that's when he kind of.
So if you ever find any Netherse artifact or need any information, just come to Hamun.
Sure, but why was he called the Black Hawk?
I have that question.
Is it because he had any of the black stones or crystals?
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
He was known as the Black Hawk for other reasons.
Let me just tell you what he was.
He was known as the Black Hawk because he wore black armor and had a habit of wearing a cape.
See, okay, that's interesting.
And so the whole idea was that he would show up with his black armor and the cape would be billowing and he would carry Talon in his hand.
He pauses and goes.
I just hope, you know, to keep up to his name when I use the sword in common.
Oh, well, he goes, that is, he smiles.
Hamun goes, yes, Pip, I hope that for you too.
And as I said, anything you find related to the Netheris, consider me your expert.
Sure, we'll do.
I still don't trust Hamun, so I and he turns to Veyra and says, And Veyra, could I take a look at your crystal if you would be so kind?
No, no, no, we don't tell him that we have the crystal.
Oh, you didn't tell him?
Not yet, no.
You don't tell him about the crystal?
No, no.
We just tell him that we came across a crystal on the way here.
Oh, you don't tell him about Veyra's blue crystal?
No, no, no.
Okay, that was my misunderstanding.
That's fine.
All right.
So, oh, yes, and you did tell Veyra to keep her mouth shut.
Yes.
Right.
Veyra, you know, has that look that people have who like can't keep their mouth shut?
Like she wants to, she's about to explode.
Right.
I don't know whether you've seen like the kind of person who walks into a meeting and is trying really hard to not say something.
Not say something, yes.
I remember she wanted to talk with the Nothic as well.
Yeah, so she's got that look of I've got to ask 100 million questions right now, right now.
Yeah, I got it.
But you managed to convince her that maybe this time she should keep her mouth shut.
And with that, we will end.
Before we end, add your give yourself another level.
Okay.
Manage character offering
level four.
Okay.
Updated.
Yes.
Yes, updated.
This is a new or recently leveled up character sheet beyond me to.
You remember to click on the there's like one, you just need to click on one of the things so it can reload the Java.
Right.
Oh, like refresh page.
Reload the page.
Please select the features and traits panel on your D and D Beyond character sheet to parse this character features and populate characters.
Okay.
If you see, if you see it under where we had the here spell, do you see it?
You click on that and it'll go away.
Yes, yes.
I've updated it.
Oh, sorry, not this one.
Right.
So if you raise your level, I think you gain a feet fourth level.
You see the features and traits.
Yeah, so okay, now go to level four.
Yeah.
Did you check?
Did you adjust your character?
Yeah, when I clicked on the features and traits, the character got adjusted.
Yeah, now click on manage.
Yeah, okay.
All right, now go to manage character levels.
I scroll up.
All right, keep going, scroll down.
All right, so click on this ability score improvement.
All right.
Here's the most annoying part of this game.
You have the ability to either raise your dexterity or any of your character ability scores or pick a feat.
What's a feat?
Oh, like one of those things.
So I don't have time to help.
I don't have time now, but if you just go through this, there's a lot of different things.
I think I gave you the link to I gave you the HTML page.
So go look it over and just pick a feat.
All right.
So, okay, just to be clear, you can either pick a feat or add two ability score points to like dexterity or whatever you want.
Right.
So if I select the ability score improvement, I can, you know, bump up your dexterity.
Any of the two scores.
Okay.
All right.
Yeah.
If I choose an athlete, then I can still improve.
So there are two kinds of feats: feats that give you an ability score improvement and some kind of bonus, and some that give you no ability score improvement, but a pretty big bonus.
So, for example, yeah, like crossbow does not just increase my dexterity, but but you can now use it within five feet.
Yes, yes.
Right.
Yeah.
Okay.
Got it.
I'll take a look at this.
Yeah.
So just take a look at this.
The other thing is go get out of here.
Go to your character sheet.
Go home.
Click on home.
Sorry, rather, click on the thing on the go all the way to the top.
You see where it has the next at the end of what's next?
Sorry.
Yes.
This one.
All right.
Go to click on spells.
Go manage spells.
Let's
go click on scroll up, scroll down.
Okay.
Click on add spells.
Yeah, you can add, you can prepare one more spell.
Okay.
All right.
So that gives you a fourth spell you can choose from.
Again, so look at all of the spells here and you can pick one.
Got it.
Okay.
Right.
So if you scroll down where it says prepare, like you to you can click on one of the prepared one, prepare ones.
Unprepare.
No, no, one.
You can click on one.
You see where it says prepare?
Prepare, yes, yes.
All right.
So you can click on one of them if you want to do that.
Now, spells that have interesting abilities, like well, you could go read the whole, go read the RPG bot thing.
Yeah.
But like, so there's some pretty cool spells.
So and they all have different abilities.
All right.
There's no, some spells are truly epically lame.
Other ones are not.
Okay.
And some spells are very situational.
Like the one time you need it, you're glad you have it.
The rest of the time, it adds no okay.
Okay.
All right.
So if you, if you could just do that before our next session, that would be awesome.
Okay.
Awesome.
I'll do that.
All right.
Yep.
Okay.
And if you don't, we'll just do it first thing next session.
All right.
So I'll do it.
I'll choose.
Yeah.
So you have the manuals.
You can even read them.
You can even read it in the manuals if you want.
Okay.
Cool.
Right.
So there's probably more spells here than there is in the manual because I've bought a lot of content and I've shared it all with you.
But like for some of the spells, you could learn and some of the basic feats.
Okay.
All right.
Yep.
All right, man.
Awesome.
This was great.
Yeah, this was fun.
This was fun.
Yep.
I had fun.
Yeah.
Oh, a couple of things.
Charging into a room and killing five bugbears is the fastest way to get a third of your party killed.
Okay, okay.
Your party is not built for mass combat.
Okay, I'll keep that in mind.
Okay.
Right.
You only have, you don't, at the third level, you don't have the ability to attack up the, to fight a big group of people.
Okay.
Understood.
Right.
It's only at the fifth level then where you can start fighting groups of people.
Understood.
When I get promoted, I can take on bigger tasks.
Yes, yeah.
So, so just I'm at an empty S3.
Right to be staff.
All right.
Just, I, I, yeah, I just want you to be aware.
Like, it's not obvious, but well, yeah, yeah, yeah, I understood.
All right.
Take care.
You don't have to be stupid.
Yes.
Yeah.
No, and that's why I kind of helped you here because I'm like going, you were acting in a way which showed that you were going to get your entire party killed.
Okay.
Got it.
Yeah.
That was a stupid thing.
It wasn't a stupid thing.
You don't understand how the game works.
No, it was a stupid thing to call out all the bugbears out of the cave.
Yes.
Yeah.
I was thinking something else.
All right.
All right, man.
See you guys next week.
Bye.